



Jens NybergSystem architect and software developer

Jens Nyberg is a Software Engineer and Software Architect with 12 years of professional experience ranging from embedded development, os & driver development, full-stack web development, big data solutions engineer, project management, system architecture designer and prototyper for telecom and spare time open source developer.

Work Experience

Nov 2016 - Ongoing Stockholm

Technology area specialist

Fricsson

Jens worked as a specialist in the area of operating systems and virtualization. He mainly did prototyping work in order to find new and better solutions for problems in Ericssons' portfolio of products. One of the bigger projects that lens came up with (together with another colleague) that gained a lot of attention was a custom-built Linux image based system which ran entirely in RAM in which Ericsson was able to deploy both it's entire IMS system and it's entire vRAN system with a mix of virtual machines and containers. This lowered the amount of compute resources needed considerably because of the little footprint and minimal configuration it had in comparison to the previous OpenStack instances and at the same time it saved a ton on maintenance and testing. The time it took to upgrade an entire cluster of machines went from weeks to literally hours (or even minutes in some cases). This was showcased and demoed all throughout Ericsson and got very positive feedback and was even presented at Mobile World Congress together with what was going to be the next generation hardware for edge deployments for which this was built. Sadly, soon after, Ericsson started to discontinue these type of deployments so the project never really had time to make it out the door.

VMware	Linux	Python	Vim	Bash	C	Docker	Mikr	otjänster
Molnlösnir	ngar	VirtualBox	OpenSt	ack	QEMU	Kubern	etes	Libvirt

May 2012 - Oct 2016 Stockholm

Software developer

Ericsson

Ericsson builds their own server blades called GEP which is part of their BSP blade system offering. Jens wrote both Linux drivers to handle custom hardware components on GEP (like the custom BMC) and tools for updating firmware like BIOS and for various disks and network devices. Not only did he do the actual development himself but as the project owner he also helped plan for upcoming revisions and synchronize the daily work items together with the hardware developers themselves. Also had meetings with representatives from Intel.

More about BSP: https://www.ericsson.com/en/portfolio/digital-services/cloud-infrastructure/bsp-8100



Apr 2011 - Apr 2012 Stockholm

Software developer

Combitech

Jens worked as a consultant for Ericsson, mainly on their custom SLES-based Linux system used in a platform know as Core Middleware. The system had already by then been around for a while so there was not much feature development so most of the time was spent handling bug reports and improving the test coverage. Pretty soon after this Jens got offered a job and moved over as a full time employee at Ericsson.



Aug 2010 - Jul 2011 Västerås

Software developer

Pingdom

The idea behind Pingdom is very simple. They monitor the server of a customer by sending pings from other machines around the world. If the server doesn't reply they notify the customer that the server is not reachable. The results of each of these pings needs to be saved and analyzed. It needs to be aggregated and made available for reading. Jens worked on trying to improve the performance in this backend that dealt with all of this data. He also improved worked on the backend for the web interface and sometimes on the frontend as well.

HTML JavaScript PHP SQL CSS C# MySQL

May 2007 - Jul 2010 Uppsala

Software developer

Trippus

Jens worked as a fullstack developer working on both the frontend (HTML, JS) as well as the backend (C#, SQL) of their travel booking system.

HTML JavaScript ASP ASP.NET SQL Subversion CSS C#

Education

Computer science Uppsala university (Uppsala)

oppsaid diliversity (oppsaid

Finished 2,5years

Courses and Certifications

Linux Device Driver and Board Support Package Development WindRiver

2016

2003 - 2006

The Linux Device Driver and Board Support Package Development course provides engineers with a fast, cost-effective way to acquire the skills necessary to develop, deploy, and debug their own customized Linux device drivers and BSPs in the Wind River® Linux environment.

Skills



Expert

C CSS HTML Operativsystem QEMU



ASP Bash Docker Git JavaScript Jenkins Libvirt Linux Mikrotjänster PHP Raspberry PI SQL Vim VirtualBox





Arduino Assembler C++ Kubernetes OpenGL OpenStack Perl Python

VMware Yocto

Languages

Swedish	Native or bilingual proficiency
English	Full professional proficiency